http://www.bowvalleycu.com/privacy-and-legal/

About Us
Our privacy commitment. As a member-owned financial institution, we are committed to developing policies, procedures, and services that protect member privacy. Privacy and the protection of personal information is not only a legislative requirement under the Personal Information Protection Act (PIPA) but also an important cornerstone to the successful operation of our credit union.Our commitment means that we will protect your privacy and respect your right to have a say in how we collect, use, or disclose your personal information. We enforce strict compliance with the legislative requirements of PIPA and our employees are trained to safeguard your information.BVCU will comply with each of the 10 privacy protection principles outlined below.Principle 1: AccountabilityWe are responsible for all personal information under our control and have designated a Privacy Officer who is accountable for our compliance with PIPA.Principle 2: Identifying PurposesWhen we ask for your personal information, we will identify the purposes for collecting, using or disclosing it in a clear and understandable way. Any new purposes will be identified prior to use and we will require your consent unless the new purpose is required by law.Principle 3: ConsentWe require your knowledge and consent for the collection, use, or disclosure of personal information.  You may withdraw your consent at any time, subject to our legal and contractual restrictions.Principle 4: Limiting CollectionThe collection of personal information will be limited to the purposes that we have identified to you. We will collect personal information by fair and lawful means and not by misleading or deceiving you about the purpose for which information is being collected.We may collect anonymous technical information when you visit our website. This technical information is used for purposes such as diagnosing problems, improving the operation and content of the website and compiling aggregate and statistical information. We use cookies on our website, however, many web browsers allow users to disable permanent and/or temporary cookies.Principle 5: Limiting Use, Disclosure, and RetentionWe will not use or disclose personal information for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with your consent or as required by law. We will securely destroy, erase, or make anonymous any personal information no longer needed for its identified purposes or for legal requirements.Principle 6: AccuracyWe will keep personal information as accurate, complete, and up-to-date, as is necessary for the purposes for which it is to be used. We have put in place processes to allow members the opportunity to have inaccurate data amended.Principle 7: SafeguardsWe will protect personal information in our custody and control with a high level of safeguards. We will safeguard personal information from loss or theft, as well as unauthorized access, use, copying, modification, disclosure, or disposal. We will only conduct business with third parties, affiliates, and processors that honour the same standards of safeguards as us.Principle 8: OpennessWe will make specific, understandable information readily available to you about our policies and procedures relating to the management of personal information.Principle 9: Individual AccessUpon written request, you will be informed of the existence, use, and disclosure of any personal information that we hold about you and given access to it. You will have the opportunity to ensure the accuracy and completeness of this information and to have it corrected if required. We will amend the information as required, subject to specific legal restrictions.Principle 10: Challenging ComplianceYou are welcome to challenge our compliance with PIPA or with our privacy policies and procedures by contacting our Privacy Officer. The Privacy Officer has implemented procedures to investigate and respond to all questions or concerns. Additional Legal Compliance:Code of Conduct for the Credit and Debit Card Industry in Canada
Contacting the Privacy OfficerThe following forms are intended to help you make a written access request, correction request, complaint, or inquiry under PIPA. Please note that you may need to produce a piece of government-issued photo identification in order to obtain the information requested for access and correction requests.Request to Access Personal Information (PIPA-1)
Request to Correct Personal Information (PIPA-2)
Filing a Privacy Complaint or Inquiry (PIPA-3)
Access requests, correction request, complaints, or inquiries should be sent to:Privacy OfficerBow Valley Credit UnionPO Box 876, Cochrane, Alberta, T4C 1A9Email: privacy@bowvalleycu.comAny person who wishes to appeal an action or decision of Bow Valley Credit Union may contact:Alberta Privacy Commissioner OfficeSuite 2460, 801 8th Avenue SW, Calgary, Alberta, T2P 3W2Email: generalinfo@oipc.ab.ca
Your branch
Canmore, Alberta
Opening Soon
9:30 am - 5:00 pm
Tomorrow
Closed
Branch details
Not your branch? Find a branch
